DAVIDE GHIOTTO

July, 2021

(VI) Italy | dghiotto.careers@gmail.com | linkedin: davide-ghiotto | github: davide97g | portfolio: davideghiotto.it

CURRICULUM VITAE

CARRIER PROFILE

Full Stack Developer with 22 months of experience implementing custom Angular Web Applications and core Java microservices, for large scale use in the banking sector. Developed reusable components and effective models to keep the pace with continuous delivery of high quality products. Managed a massive database migration activity.

Core competences include: Angular, Java, Node.js, web API, TypeScript, Firebase, JavaScript, SQL, MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, Spring, Git, HTML, CSS, Sass.

EXPERIENCE

Zucchetti S.p.A

April 2021 to July 2021

Data Scientist

Stage

Built an online interactive platform for the introduction of data science topics inside the company. Developed custom algorithms for time-series analysis and unsupervised learning

- Organized the architecture for a wide online library of machine-learning algorithms implemented in JavaScript
- Developed custom machine-learning algorithms for time-series analysis and unsupervised learning, targeting the specific problems of the company

Reply S.p.A - Cluster & Core Financial Services

Nov 2019 to present

Full Stack Developer & Database Manager

Developed complete Angular Web Applications, integrated with backend Java API, in a microservice oriented architecture, in order to build a large scale platform capable of handling the complexity of financial services world.

Managed a massive database migration to a SQL Server environment.

Implemented high quality code to speed up further developments and lower maintenance work in a continuous delivery environment.

- Created a generalized conceptual model to efficiently handle user interactions and data flow leading to an uniformed solution capable of avoid potential error situations and repetitive work
- Implemented a decentralized error handling strategy to avoid single point of failure with an increased reliability of the
- Improved data retrieval time through careful analysis and optimization of database's requests along with asynchronous client-side code
- Accelerated the procedure of database migration thanks to the development of scripts for automated quality control

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Web technologies: Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Sass
- Backend technologies: Nodejs, Java, Python, Spring
- Database: MongoDB, MySQL, POSTGRES, ORACLE
- Cloud Platform: Firebase, Google Cloud Platform, Heroku
- Data Science: R. Python, Pandas, Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit-learn
- Versioning: Git, Github, Bitbucket

EDUCATION

Master's Degree Data Science

University of Study of Padua

2019 to present

Bachelor's Degree Computer Science

University of Study of Padua

110L/110

2016-2019

Highschool Graduation 87/100

29.3/30 weighted average

Liceo Scientifico Statale G.B. Quadri

2011-2016

CERTIFICATES

• **B2** First, 2015

OTHER SKILLS

Languages English: professional proficiency. Italian: native.